Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
- Correspondence and other papers, ca. 1886-1939, HUG 4255
  - Correspondence
    - General Correspondence
      - C (Box Box 36)
        Cobb, Mary S.
        Cobb, Dr. Stanley
        Codman, Dr. E. A.
        Cohen, Simon
        Coit, Ruth (2)
        Coler, Bird S.
        Colon, George E. (2)
        Comstock, President Ada
        Comstock, Arlene S.
        Conant, Richard K., Commissioner, Public Welfare, Massachusetts.
        Conner, Dr. Lewis A.
        Cornell, Dr. William P.
        Crile, Dr. George W.
        Crockett, Dr. N. A.
        Crosson, Kate
        Crothers, Dr. S. M.
        Crothers, Mrs. S.M. (2)
        Cunningham, Edith P.
        Cunningham, Hester (3)
        Curtis, Frances G.
        Cushing, Harvey, M.D.
        Cutler, Dr. E. G.
      - D-F (Box Boxes 37-38)
        Dalton, Mrs. Ethel
        Dalton, L. G.
        Daly, Reginald A.
        Daly, Mrs. Reginald A.
        Danforth, Miss Margaret (5)
        D'Angelo, Pascal (letters re)
        Daniel, Thomas H.
        Darrow, Clarence (letter re, from Chicago Tribune)
        Darling, Grace (many)
        Darling, Harriet L. B.
        Darling, Herbert Henry
        Davidson, Thomas (3)
        Davis, Anna H. (many)
        Davis, Professor Jerome, (and copy of answer)
        Davis, Samuel G.
        Dempsy, Claire
        Denison, Mrs. Henry S.
        DeNormandie, Rev. James
        Derr, John S.
        Derr, Norman ("Mademoiselle Miss", 3 letters and MS, 1917)
        DeSelincourt, Anne Douglas Sedgwick
        DeSelincourt, Basil (7)
        Dexter, J. E.
        Dicks, Rev. Russell L.
        Doane, T. A.
        Dodge, Miss Sally
        Doe, Jessie (and copy of answer)
        Dole, Rev. Charles F.
        Dorsey, Elizabeth (1889)
        Doty, Madeleine Z. (4)
        Dow, Mrs. Fayette (Margaret Elder) (4)
        Drake, Mrs. Durant (3)
        Draper, Eben S., Governor of Massachusetts
        Drinker, Mrs. Sophie
        Dunbar, Anna L. (5, 1891-1892)
        Dunham, Dr. Theodore
        Dunn, Mary N.
        Dutton, Robert L.
        Dye, Rev. Royal J., M.D.
        Eaton, Bertha L. (4, 1908-1911)
        Eayrs, Jesse V.
        Edes, Robert
        Edsall, Dr. David L. (1917)
        Edler, Mrs. S. J.
        Eliot, Charles W. (5, 1917 ff.)
        Ellis Memorial Club (1922)
        Emerson, Haven, M.D. (and copy of answer, 1924)
        Ernst, Dr. Harold L.
        Evans, Mrs. Glendower (many, 1897-1929)
        Ewer, Bernard C.
        Farley, Beth
        Faxon, Nathaniel W. (1937)
        Fairchild, Lucia (2, 1887)
        Fairchild, Sally (1885)
        Federal Council of Churches in America (1933)
        Felden, Dr. Ladislac Gyori (Group Medicine in Cuba, 1937)
        Ferguson, C. (2, 1902)
        Fifield, James W., Jr. (and copy of answer)
        Fiske, Annie W. (5, 1887-?)
        Fletcher, Ruth E.
        Flinch, Freda (4, 1903-1904)
        Flower, Mrs. Lida (3)
        Follett, Mary P. (3, 1933)
        Forbes, Edith (6, 1886-1903)
        Forbes, Elizabeth (1910)
        Forbes, Waldo (2)
        Ford, Sarah Louise (re Mrs. Campbell)
        Fraser, Catharine I.
        Friedman, Louis M.
        Friedrich, Carl J. (and copy of answer, 1938)
        Fuller, Lucia
        Fuller, Mary B. (many letters, 1908-1914)
        Fuller, Violet (3)
        Furse, Dame Katharine (3, 1934-1936)
      - G-H (Box Box 39)
        Galbraith, J. D. (2, 1894)
        Gale, Hilda (2)
        Gale, Jane Winsor
        Gallivan, Dr. William J. (1911)
        Garrett, Francine (many letters, 1916-1917)
        Gaudelet, Louise (2)
        Gehring, Dr. Edwin W. (1906)
        Getting, Mme. Georges (4, 1919-1938)
        Gilman, Charlotte Perkins (2, 1904)
        Gleason, W. F. (4, 1901)
        Glenn, J. M. (1911)
        Glenny, Anna
        Glenny, Bryant B. (1909)
        Glueck, Eleanor T. (1931)
        Goding, Miss Emily (2, 1934, 1939)
        Goldthwaite, Dr. Joel E. (2, 1909, 1910)
        Gould, Mrs. William J. (1935)
        Graham, H., M.D.
        Grant, Rev. E. Milton (1937)
        Greene, Dr. D. Crosby
        Greene, Rev. Oscar F. (Honesty in use of historic creeds. 1938)
        Greenough, C. N. (1914)
        Greenslet, Ferris (3, and copy of answer, 1937)
        Guerrier, Edith (and copy of answer)
        Group Health Association (correspondence, 1938)
        Guild, C. E., Jr. (1893)
        Guild, Eleanor (14, 1889-1891)
        Guild Katharine (1891)
        Guild, Marion P. (1909)
        Gulick, Charlotte V. (4, 1911)
        Gulick, Luther (3, 1909)
        Gunn, Sidney (1911)
        Hadden, Maude M. (Mrs. Alexander) (1938)
        Hale, Edward Everett (1888)
        Hall, Virginia
        Hallowell, Lucretia M. (1894)
        Hamilton, Dr. Annie Lee
        Hamlen, Elizabeth P. (7, 1886-1914)
        Hamlin, Fanny Rodman (1909)
        Hanks, Mary C. (1938)
        Hanks, N. C. (1927, and copy of letter from R.C.C.)
        Hanson, Dr. William C. (1938)
        Har, K. D. (2, 1934)
        Harding, Victor M. (1938)
        Hardwick, Katharine D.
        Harkins, Rev. George F.
        Harper, Grace (7, 1913-1917)
        Harris, Mary O. (1909)
        Hart, Marion (5, 1934)
        Harvard College, correspondence with: Letters re: appt., 1902, 1908
        Letters re: retirement, 1934
        "Harvard What of the Night?" Tercentenary poem and letter of R.C.C. to Herman Hagedorn, 1936.
        Haskell, A. M. (1887)
        Haskell, Mrs. Adam (N. Hewlett) (5, 1911-1935)
        Haskell, Alice
        Haskell, H. A. (1938)
        Haskell, Marion (1913)
        Hayden, E. M.
        Hayes, Hammond V. (1906)
        Hayward, Irene
        Heath, I. A.
        Hemmeter, Dr. John C. (1911)
        Henderson, George Dallas, M.D. (1938)
        Herrick, Everett C., President, Andover Newton Theological School, and copy of answer.
        Hewson, Mrs. Madeleine Richards (1898-1902)
        Heyl, Julia
        Hicks, C. J. (1933) (2)
        Higgins, Alice L.
        Higginson, Henry L. (2, and MS on C. E. Norton)
        Higginson, Thomas Wentworth (1905)
        Hill, Edward Burlingame (3, 1910)
        Hiltner, Dr. Walter G. (1910)
        Hobart, Mary J., M.D. (enclosing letter from Dr. Cordelia Greene)
        Hocking, Professor W. E.
        Hocking, Mrs. W. E.
        Hocking, Richard (2, 1935)
        Hocking, Joan (1935)
        Hogan, Lucy (many letters, 1934-1937)
        Holbrook, Elizabeth L. (2, and copy of answer, 1930, 1931)
        Holman, Fannie (1884)
        Holt, Florence L.
        Holt, Dr. William L. (testimony re: quacks, 1916)
        Honeij, Dr. James A. (1910)
        Honesty, reviews on (1939)
        Houghton, Elizabeth H. (1903)
        Howe, Fannie R. (3, 1906, 1909)
        Hughes, Henry F.
        Humphreys. Charles A. (re Brookline Church, 1887)
        Hunt, Rev. John E. (and copy of answer)
        Hunt, Mavis (1909)
        Hunter, Rev. David R. (1935)
        Hunter, Sally (1914)
        Huntington, Mrs. Ellen B. (10, 1911-1915)
      - I-L (Box Box 40)
        Irish Lament, music of.
        Irvine, George (1893)
        Jackson, Anna P. (1912)
        Jackson, Charles (re Community Fund, 1939)
        Jackson, Fannie E. (1894)
        Jackson, Frances (3, 1903)
        James, William (5, 1898-1904)
        Janeway, Eleanor C.
        Janeway, Dr. Theodore C. (2, 1912, 1913)
        January, Josephine P.
        Johns Hopkins University
        Johnson, Professor and Mrs. Franklin
        Jones, Mrs. I. Howland (Edith Richie) (5, 1909-1917)
        Kane, Florence Bayard (2, 1909, 1911)
        Kay, T. W.
        Keller, Helen (2, 1909)
        Kern, Penelope V. (2)
        Kayes, Dr. Edward L. Jr.
        Kimball, Anna (many letters, 1909-1917, and small sketchbook)
        King, Gertrude L.
        Kingsley, S. C.
        Lafarge, Florence
        LaFarge, Rev. John (1912)
        Laighton, Ruth (4)
        Lang, Angela
        Lang, Malcolm (1915)
        Lang, Margaret R. (1916)
        Laverack, Belle (3, and MS)
        Lawrence, Rt. Rev. William (1887, 1939)
        Lawson, Mary Rowley (9, 1904-1910)
        Leatherbee, Harriet B. (1902)
        Leavitt, Mary E. (1911)
        Lee, Alice (2, 1938)
        Lee, Gerald Stanley (1909)
        Lee, George Winthrop
        Lee, John (1939)
        Lee, Joseph (3, 1903-1917, copy of one from R.C.C.)
        Leland, Cora Josephine (1893)
        Leonard, "Vaudevillian" (telegram, 1910?)
        Leonard, W. E. (copy of letter to G. W. Allport)
        Likhareff, Mme. Zenaide (7)
        Lincoln, Alice M. (1912)
        Littlefield, A. M. (1908)
        Livingston, Mary (6, 1892-1893)
        Lodge, A. C. M.
        Lodge, Henry Cabot (1906)
        Longstock, Morris
        Loring, Mary G. (2, 1904)
        Loveland, Fred H. (3, 1893)
        Loveland, Dr. John E. (1934)
        Lovell, Mrs. Walter (2)
        Lovich-Best, Mrs. Ivan (many letters)
        Lowell, J. S. (1887)
        Lyman, Arthur T.
        Lyman, Mrs. Arthur (many letters, 1886-1934)
        Lyman, Arthur T. Jr. (1935)
        Lyman, Miss Julia (8, 1905)
        Lyman, Mrs. Herbert (8)
        Lyman, Ella (Mrs. Roger I. Lee, 1914)
        Lyman, George L. (2)
        Lyman, Miss Mabel (2)
        Lyon, Rev. W. H.
        Lyons, Louis M. (n.d.)
      - Ada P. McCormick to Richard C. Cabot (Box Box 41)
      - M-O (Box Box 42)
        Correspondent
        MacKenzie, Dr. J. (1908)
        MacLennan, Rev. David A. (and copy of answer, 1927)
        Macmillan Company (9, and copy of answers, 1936-38)
        Macy, Etta
        Main, Roscoe C. (3, 1910)
        Mallock, Douglas (2 letters and copy of verses "The Model Man", 1932)
        Manahan, Dr. T. J. (of ship "Bay State"; obituary, 1911)
        Maramian, Mary (1904)
        Maria, Sister (1919)
        Mason, Daniel Gregory (1934)
        Mason, Fanny P. (10, 1888-1910)
        Mason, Mary Gertrude (1907)
        Massachusetts Civic League (and copy of answer, 1924)
        Massachusetts Volunteer Aid Assn. (Spanish War, 1898)
        Maxwell, Anna C. (1904)
        May, Louise C. (1897)
        May, Sarah Russell
        McManus, George (1939)
        McSweeney, Edward F. (1909)
        Mead, Frances
        Means, Frederick H.
        Meltzer, S. J. (1913)
        Mendelsohn, Louis, M. D. (1933)
        Merrick, Bertha V. (2, 1889, 1892)
        Miano, Agnes (many letters, 1910-1914)
        Milburn, Devereux ("Ethics of Sport")
        Miller, Dickinson S. (1899-1901, 1906)
        Miller, Dr. George N. (1906)
        Mills College (2 letters from President Reinhardt, 1934)
        Milstein, Mrs. Celia Block (1937)
        Minis, Mary Haskell (1903-1934)
        Minns, Grace W. (1904?)
        Minor, Marie L. (1902)
        Minot, Elizabeth V. P. (1891)
        Mitchell, Dr. Weir
        Mix, B. Huntington (1911)
        Moffitt, H. C.
        Morgan, Anne (many letters, 1890-1909)
        Morgan, Ruth (2, 1920, 1934)
        Moors, John F.
        Moors, Maria P. (2, 1887?)
        Montague, Margaret P. (many letters, 1910-?)
        Morley, Margaret W.
        Moss, Rev. Charles H. (1911)
        Mudie, R. C. (1903)
        Mueller, F. F. (1934)
        Mumford, Dr. George S. (1915)
        Munn, Margaret C. (1892-?)
        Munroe, James P. ("Boston 1915")
        Munroe, Dr. and Mrs. George E.
        Murphy, William T.
        Musser, Dr. John H.
        Neergard, Alice Mead (1937)
        New Jersey, State of (1909)
        Nicati-de Luze, Mme. Germaine (many letters, 1919-1939)
        Nichols, Dr. Robert H. (3, 1911)
        Oakman, Georgie Clark (2, 1893)
        O'Brien, John R., M. D. (1903)
        O'Gorman, Alice G. (3, 1911-1936)
        Oliver, Thomas (1908)
        O'Malley, Austin, M. D. (1913)
        Ordway, C. A. (1904)
        Ordway, Julia K. (4, 1904)
        Ordway, Thomas (3, 1904)
        Osann, Charlotte (2 and MS, 1938, 1939)
        Osgood, Dr. Robert B. (2, 1934, 1939)
        Osler, Sir William (6, Interurban Club)
      - P-R (Box Box 43)
        Padelford, Frank W. (Colby College, 1938)
        Painter, Adelaide E. (7, 1900?)
        Painter, Florence (many letters, 1900-?)
        Palmer, George H. (1909)
        Palmer, Rev. Kenneth L. (and copies of answers, 1937)
        Parkinson, William D. (1911)
        Parkman, Frances (Mrs. Henry) (4, 1904-1905)
        Parry, Dr. Angenette (2, 1932-1934)
        Parry, Dr. Eleanor (3, 1900-1939)
        Passmore, Charlotte (1920)
        Passmore, Sarah (2, 1909, 1920)
        Pavlidis, Dr. Isaac (2, 1911, 1912)
        Payn-Sills, Lillian
        Peabody, A. M. (re Mrs. Campbell, 1904)
        Peabody, Francis G. (2, 1911, 1933)
        Peabody, George L. (1901?)
        Pelton, Garnet L. (many letters, Social Service Dept. 1904-1908)
        Pepperell, Margaret (2, 1893)
        Perkins, C. E. (1887)
        Perkins, Rev. John Carroll (1933)
        Perkins, Katrine (Mrs. James)
        Perkins, Olga (1903)
        Perkins, S. S. (many letters, n.d.)
        Pernession, Noemi Cabot (4, 1906)?)
        Phi Beta Kappa (Henry Preble, Sec'y, 1888)
        Phillips, J. S. (American Magazine, 1911)
        Pigors, Paul (1933)
        Pigors, Sylvia (1935)
        Place, Charles A. (1903)
        Poor, Mary W. (1903)
        Porter, Bruce (5, 1900-1914)
        Porter, Allen (1898)
        Porter, C. A. (1903)
        Pottle, Mrs. Juliet Wilbor Tompkins (many letters)
        Pratt, Dr. F. W. (M.G.H., 1891-1892)
        Prenn, Joseph, M. D.
        Prince, Morton, M. D. (1912)
        Pringle, Rev. J. C. (1936)
        Purrington, W. A. (1908)
        Putnam, C. L. R. (1890)
        Putnam, Elizabeth C. (letter and MS, 1893)
        Putnam, Dr. James J. (4, 1904-1912)
        Putnam, Marion C. (to E. T. Cabot, 1886)
        Rainsford, W. S. (1913)
        Rhoades, Winfred (and copy of answer, 1923)
        Richards, Elizabeth H. (1909-1911)
        Richards, John (1897)
        Richardson, Dr. Maurice N.H. (1916)
        Richmond, Mary P. (1911)
        Righter, Rose (1909)
        Robbins, R. C. (3, 1900-1903)
        Robins, Colonel Raymond
        Robins, Mrs. Raymond (5, 1937-1939)
        Rochester, Anna
        Rodman, Cornelia B.
        Rogers, Mabel Hubbard (4, 1913-1914)
        Rolleston, Sir H. D., M. D. (2, 1908)
        Roma, Dr. Ernesto
        Root, Pauline (1914)
        Royce, Josiah (12, 1899-1916)
        Russell, Alys (1908)
        Russell, Mrs. Bess Lynde (5, 1920)
        Russell, Helena
      - S (Box Box 44)
        Sage, Katherine (several)
        Salmonde, Hubert
        Samoylenko, Dr. Elisabeth (1935)
        Samper, Doris Baldwin (3, 1934)
        Sampson, David W.
        Sampson, Lilian V. (1891)
        Santayana, George (1899)
        Sarton, May (3, and poem)
        Sayre, Francis B. (and copy of answer, 1938)
        Schaeffer, Le. E.
        Schauffler, Robert H. (1911)
        Scientific Temperance Federation (and copy of answer)
        Seaman, Lillie
        Sears, Annie L.
        Sears, Mary (many letters, 1894-1926)
        Sears, Sarah P.
        Sedgwick, Ellery (2, 1909, 1910)
        Shaler, N. S. (1903)
        Shattuck, Dr. F. C. (7)
        Shaw, Pauline A. (1899)
        Sheldon, Joseph
        Sherman, Ethel B. (re Miss Halford, 1935)
        Sherrill, Arthur M. (1938)
        Sidebotham, Maud
        Simes, E. (Charity Organisation, London, 1908)
        Simons, Grace C. (1910)
        Singer, Jacob (and copy of answer, 1928)
        Smith, Annie Hatheway (1893)
        Smith, B. E. (1893)
        Smith, Mrs. Edith (letter and poem)
        Smith, Elton E. (1939)
        Smith, Zilpha D. (1910)
        Smoot, Sadie (12, 1891-1894)
        Sorokin, Pa A. (2, and copies of answers, 1934)
        Southard, O. W. (Mrs. E. E.) (1920)
        Southworth, W. S. (1921)
        Speer, Emma Bailey (1913)
        Sprague, F. P. (2, 1903, 1909)
        Stauffer, Henry (re Rev. Mr. Eitzen, 1938)
        Stefanova, Stefanka (1933)
        Steffens, Lincoln (1911)
        Stockton, Dr. Charles (many letters, 1906-1916)
        Stockton, Lucy (many letters, 1906-1916)
        Storer, Agnes (re Irene Hayward, 1938)
        Storer, Edith (1934)
        Storer, Emily (1934)
        Storer, Maria Longworth (Mrs. Bellamy) (2, 1912)
        Storrow, Helen (Mrs. James J.
        Stowell, C. Channing (1893)
        Street School (letter from Prof. Hall and copy of answer, 1938)
        Sutton, Dr. Walter S. (1911)
      - T-Y (Box Box 45)
        Includes unidentified letters and fragments; and letters to R.C.C. re. What Men Live By.
        Tack, Violet (4, 1908-1909)
        Taylor, Dr. Edward W. (1909)
        Taylor, Dr. Harry B.
        Taylor, Dr. Quintard
        Tenney, Dr. Albert S. (1909)
        Thaw, Dr. A. Blair (1901)
        Thayer, Abbott H. (5, n.d.)
        Thompson, Mrs. Lewis S. (5, 1934)
        Thompson, Alyz M.
        Towns, Charles B. (1917)
        Trehoar, Ethel (1914)
        Trudeau, Dr. Edward L. (n.d.)
        Trumbell, C. G. ("A Lie Never Justifiable", 3, 1903-1909)
        Ulrich, Mabel S. (4, n.d.)
        Vaughan, Ellen
        Viets, Dr. Henry R. (1938)
        Wadsworth, Lucy C.
        Wall, Marcia Cary
        Walsh, Ethel
        Walsh, Dr. James J.
        Walter, Cornelia
        Waltham place, letters re. (1937)
        Warner, Rev. Robert R. (1933)
        Warren, Charles (1910)
        Warren, Gretchen (Mrs. Fiske) (8, 1893-?)
        Warren, W. R. and R. C. Cabot, "Report of the Committee on Philosophy," 1908.
        Webster, Edith, F.
        Weld, Julia B. (1902)
        Wendell, Barrett (1899)
        Wernts, R. L. (1911)
        Westbrook, Dr. F. F. (1904)
        Wharton, Frances W. (1902)
        What Men Live By, letters about. (1914 ff.)
        White, Alfred T. (Department of Social Ethics, 1920)
        White, Amy (1888)
        White, Gaylord S. (1910)
        White, John W. (R. C. C. honors in Classics, 1887)
        Whiting, Mrs. Charles (1936)
        Whitman, Mrs. Sarah (17, 1887-1904, with R.C.C.'s notes)
        Whittier, Nancy (2, 1939)
        Wilkinson, Julia (1911)
        Williams and Wilkins, publishers, (re. Physical Diagnosis, and copies of answers, 1938)
        Wilson, D. M. (1887)
        Wilson, Dr. Philip
        Wilson, Susan E. (2, 1910)
        Winslow, Mrs. Frederick (1935)
        Wister, Owen (2, 1915)
        Withers, Frances
        Withington, Mrs. Lena Lewis (2, and MS notes, 1912-1915)
        Wolcott, Claire
        Woodbury, Augustus (1887)
        Worcester, Dr. Alfred (1894)
        Worcester, Elizabeth (Mrs. Alfred)
        Worcester, Dr. Eldwood (2, n.d.)
        Wright, Wade, M. D. (1919)
        Young, Edward J. (1897)
      - Letters received after the Death of Mrs. Cabot, September 20, 1934 (Box Box 46)
  - Teaching Notes
    - Social Ethics (Sociology 2) "Human Relations"
      - Early notes and supplementary material on Confidence, Veracity, Property; Relations of Men and Women; On Lying. (Box Box 47)
      - Notes for lectures and stenographic reports of lectures., 1920-1921 (Box Box 48)
      - Lectures, supplementary material, and students' papers., 1933-1934 (Box Box 49-50)
        These folders used at Harvard and Radcliffe, but not at Andover-Newton.
      - Notes of course as last given, drawing on notes from previous years., 1937-1938 (Box Box 51)
      - Notes on Property, Mr. Hicks, Labor Ethics. Class and section lists. Marking lists from all courses. (Box Box 52)
      - Notebook: "Use of Agencies and Social Case Work," Andover-Newton, 1934-1935
      - Industrial relations; business ethics. (Box Boxes 53-55)
      - Industrial relations; Spies. (Box Box 56)
      - Industrial Relations. Notes on property. Notes of field trips. Assigned readings. (Box Box 57)
      - Relations of Men and Women. Race Relations. (Box Box 58)
      - International Relations. War. (Box Box 59)
      - International Relations. War. Princeton Meeting on Industrial Relations. (Box Box 60)
      - Supplementary Notes on Ethics
        - Absolute Desire and Agreement (Box Box 61)
          The unconditional desire (Growth)
          Absolute morality
        - Agreement, Internal (Hocking, James, Royce) (Box Box 61)
        - Agreement, Process of (Box Box 61)
        - Agreement, Stone Behind Wheel (Box Box 61)
        - Agreement, Objections and Answers (Box Box 61)
        - Agreement, Why needed (Box Box 61)
        - Argument (Box Box 61)
        - Authority (Box Box 61)
        - Blame (incl. two letters from H. Croly) and Necessity (Box Box 61)
        - Clearing the Decks, Elliott Smith on (Box Box 61)
        - Conscience (Box Box 61)
        - Courage (Box Box 61)
        - Decisiveness (Box Box 61)
        - Desires (all singly good) (Box Box 61)
        - Destruction in Growth (Box Box 61)
        - John Dewey (see also Reading Notes) (Box Box 61)
        - Due Care (Box Box 61)
        - Edges and exactness (Box Box 61)
        - Facing Reality (Box Box 61)
        - Finding Oneself (Box Box 61)
        - Forking vs. Synthesis (Box Box 61)
        - Faults (Student's lists; Nietzsche's lists) (Box Box 61)
        - Growth (Box Box 61)
          Fragments on Growth
          Altruism and Growth
          Assimilation and Growth
          Attention and Growth
          Concealment of Growth
          Creativeness and Growth
          Dewey on Growth
          Emerson and E.L.C. on Growth
          Enjoyment and Growth
          Essentials of Growth
          Examples of Growth, per letter and spirit
          Facts and Growth
          3 Fates of Growth
          Freedom and Growth
          Growing edge the focus of duty for each
          Human Aims of Growth
          Intuition, Vision, Revelation and Growth
          Leadership and Growth
          Manifestations of Growth
          Means, ends, and growth [causes and effects]
          Needs, Agreements, and Growth
          Sanctimony and growth
          Social Work and Growth
          Stagnation and Growth
          Stimuli to Growth
          Synonyms of Growth
          Tests of Growth
          Time of Growth
          Whitehead on Growth
          Basil and Bridges on Beauty and Growth
          Revelation and Growth
          Growth as Master Desire
          Royce's scheme of the concept of growth
        - Happiness (Kant and Durant Drake) (Box Box 61)
        - Human Relations (Survey of types and problems) (Box Box 61)
        - Imagination; Inside and Outside (point of view) (Box Box 61)
        - Introductory Material on Ethics (Box Box 61)
        - Labelling (pamphlet: "Moral Judgments of High School Students," Slavens Brogan) (Box Box 61)
        - Justice (Whewell on) (Box Box 61)
        - Good, Good Act, etc., Kant on. (Box Box 61)
        - Laziness (Box Box 61)
        - Leisure (Box Box 61)
        - Manners (Box Box 61)
        - Mental Hygiene (see also reading notes) (Box Box 61)
        - Morals and Law (Box Box 61)
        - Motives and Consequences (Box Box 61)
        - Logical Necessity and Ethics (Box Box 61)
          "Important material to be kneaded into Growth"
        - Needs (absolute) split from desire (Box Box 61)
          Notes on R.B. Perry's criticism of The Meaning of Right and Wrong MS
        - Needs and how to list them (cf. Values) (Box Box 62)
        - Non-ethical element in conduct; Ethical neutrality (the "permissible"). (Box Box 62)
        - Old and Young and Difficult People (Box Box 62)
        - Outcroppings of Ethical Interest (Box Box 62)
        - Penance; Prayer and the Prepared Mind (Box Box 62)
        - Progress and Individuality (Box Box 62)
        - Publicity and Privacy (Box Box 62)
        - Quantitative Ethics (Box Box 62)
          R.C.C.'s notes on Perry's Ethics
        - Ethical Reflection (Box Box 62)